<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Institutional RSE Networking</title><link>https://usrse.github.io/ag-institutional-rse-networking/</link><description>Recent content on Institutional RSE Networking</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:42:44 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://usrse.github.io/ag-institutional-rse-networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>December Meetup Summary—Communities and People!</title><link>https://usrse.github.io/ag-institutional-rse-networking/posts/2025-12-meeting-recap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:42:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://usrse.github.io/ag-institutional-rse-networking/posts/2025-12-meeting-recap/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="communities-are-made-up-of-people"&gt;
 Communities Are Made up of People
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#communities-are-made-up-of-people"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our December meetup, we had chosen two podcast episodes for discussion. Both episodes were from the &lt;a href="https://www.opensourcestories.org/"&gt;Open Source Stories podcast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.opensourcestories.org/stories/2024/andy-piper-community-needs/"&gt;Changing communities have changing needs with Andy Pipe&lt;/a&gt;r&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.opensourcestories.org/stories/2023/community-health-and-belonging/"&gt;Community health and belonging with Anita Ihuman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While focusing on open source communities and not on building local communities around a career choice, both episodes were very insightful and applicable to our problem at hand: how can we build and sustain a local RSE community at our institutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>November Meetup Summary—Totally Worth Reading!</title><link>https://usrse.github.io/ag-institutional-rse-networking/posts/2025-11-meeting-recap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:42:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://usrse.github.io/ag-institutional-rse-networking/posts/2025-11-meeting-recap/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="building-a-communityits-the-economy-vision-stupid"&gt;
 Building a Community&amp;mdash;It&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;del&gt;economy&lt;/del&gt; vision, stupid!
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#building-a-communityits-the-economy-vision-stupid"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 18, 2025, the institutional networking affinity group got together to discuss “&lt;a href="https://www.bluecoding.com/post/10-best-practices-for-building-a-strong-remote-developer-community"&gt;10 recommended practices for creating a robust community of remote developers&lt;/a&gt;”. Ok, we’ll be honest, it was just J.C. and Julia, but it was a very productive discussion. In this blog post, we’ll summarize the discussion highlights for everyone who could not be at the meeting or for whomever stumbles across this post in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NURSEs.xlsx</title><link>https://usrse.github.io/ag-institutional-rse-networking/posts/2025-05_js/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 14:42:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://usrse.github.io/ag-institutional-rse-networking/posts/2025-05_js/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the ever-evolving world of research software engineering (RSE), collaboration and community are key to success. Recently, I had the opportunity to connect with my colleague, Luke Rasmussen, through USRSE’s Slack group. Both of us, working remotely, decided to meet via Zoom to discuss our shared vision for creating a vibrant RSE community at Northwestern University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our conversation was fueled by a common desire to empower and motivate each other as software engineers. We envisioned a space where siloed developers could connect, share ideas, and contribute to individual grants. This community would not only foster professional growth but also provide a supportive environment for all involved.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Let's Get Them in a Room!</title><link>https://usrse.github.io/ag-institutional-rse-networking/posts/2025-04_jd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 14:38:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://usrse.github.io/ag-institutional-rse-networking/posts/2025-04_jd/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I work remotely for Arizona State University (ASU), but from time to time I get to go back to Arizona and meet people in person. When I went back in April of this year, my colleague Susan Massey and I planned an in-person meeting of RSEs that work across ASU. For context, at this point we have an informal group of people doing RSE work at ASU. We meet monthly and each meeting is usually attended by somewhere between 4 and 7 people. Our network is a little bit bigger than the people who usually show up for our meetings, but it’s still tiny compared to how many RSEs there must be at ASU (which has over 18,000 employees and over 5,000 faculty). Susan and I set out with the goal to make this the biggest RSE meeting at ASU so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>QR Redirect</title><link>https://usrse.github.io/ag-institutional-rse-networking/qr/usrse25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://usrse.github.io/ag-institutional-rse-networking/qr/usrse25/</guid><description>&lt;meta http-equiv="refresh" content="0; url=https://usrse.github.io/ag-institutional-rse-networking/"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are not redirected, &lt;a href="https://usrse.github.io/ag-institutional-rse-networking/"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>